<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-05T10:38:21+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Worldwide Walkabouts</title><subtitle>Ramblings of a nomadic software engineer, photographer, and adventurer :)</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Final Thoughts on Over a Year of Travel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/01/03/final-thoughts-on-over-a-year-of-travel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Final Thoughts on Over a Year of Travel" /><published>2019-01-03T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/01/03/final-thoughts-on-over-a-year-of-travel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2019/01/03/final-thoughts-on-over-a-year-of-travel.html">&lt;p&gt;I remember the day I went into my supervisor’s office, intent on quitting my job. I was a nervous wreck. I walked around the office, past his door, a few times before actually going in. Countless thoughts were spiraling around in my head: How will he react? Will I be fired immediately? Could I ever find another job again? What am I going to do when I run out of money? But none of these questions stopped me. I knew what I wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quitting my job was the first brave step I had taken on my journey. My outward journey, and my inward journey. Although I traveled through a dozen different countries, what I took away from it was not the places I visited. The lessons I learned about myself were far more rewarding than any place I visited. While traveling on my journey, I improved myself in countless ways, I met people who changed my thinking, and I made tons of mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons&quot;&gt;Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving myself was always on the forefront of my mind while I was traveling. I wanted to become a better person. But what does “better” mean? For me, I wanted to become more social, be less anxious, have more patience, increase my empathy, learn new skills, practice humility, and raise my awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling around the world makes it easy to learn these things. By going out of my comfort zone and talking with people, I improved my sociability and empathy. By choosing to work in areas where I had no expertise, I not only learned new skills, but I also practiced humility. When I missed flights, trains, buses, got lost, or made other mistakes, I learned to have patience and worry less. And by working on myself, I met so many incredible people in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people you meet while traveling will leave impressions on you for life. Some of them are good, some of them are bad, and some of them are just down right incredible. I met countless other travelers from everywhere around the world. People of all different backgrounds, ages, races, nationalities, and reasons for traveling. Each person I met had a different story to tell. And no matter what their story, I could learn something from it. Each chance I got to meet another person, I jumped at the opportunity. I believe that every person on this planet is just you living a different life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mistakes&quot;&gt;Mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, it wasn’t all fun. I made plenty of mistakes. Some of which I regret daily. But those mistakes taught me some of my most important lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started traveling, I wanted to visit places. Places that I had heard wonderful things about. Some of the first mistakes I made were because I wanted to just travel somewhere. I wanted to leave my current moment to find my next adventure. But every time I did that, I left new friends behind in the process, and I regretted it. Now, I travel for friends. If I have an opportunity to keep traveling with people I met on the road, I take it. It doesn’t matter if it was in the original plan. I learned to value the friendships I made, over the places I wanted to visit. And I still had incredible experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned that I need a purpose while traveling. I need to be working on myself, helping others, or even just trekking a difficult trail. At first, I traveled for things I wanted to do or places I wanted to see. But I found that when I had a purpose, like volunteering or working, I enjoyed my time more. Finding a place where I could learn new skills or help others made the place I was in a paradise. If I didn’t have a purpose, I felt lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I apply everything I learned. I travel to meet up with old friends, find new friends, work on myself, or help others in need. When I focus on the important aspects of traveling, the rest falls into place. And you end up having epic adventures with awesome people anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m unbelievably lucky to have had the opportunity to travel for a year. It has taught me so much. Although I am starting a new full-time job in a few days, I hope that I can apply what I’ve learned to my everyday life. And I know that one day, I will travel again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Learning invaluable lessons, meeting incredible people, and making many mistakes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Northern Vietnam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/vietnam/2018/12/21/exploring-northern-vietnam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Northern Vietnam" /><published>2018-12-21T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/vietnam/2018/12/21/exploring-northern-vietnam</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/vietnam/2018/12/21/exploring-northern-vietnam.html">&lt;p&gt;After over one year of traveling around the world, I had to choose my last stop. I thought about where I would want to go. I thought about what I had learned over the past year. I thought about how I had changed. I thought about how I learned to value people and relationships over places and things. I learned to travel not for the destination, but for the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of traveling to a country for some place I had read about, I traveled for a friend. I decided to travel to Vietnam to meet someone I met while volunteering in Nepal. I met Van one day at a goat pen close to the school we were building. We struck up a conversation which eventually led to agreeing to run together. Our run turned into a hike, which turned into a walk, which turned into us sitting on the side of a hill talking. I had so much admiration for her that day as she told me stories of her travels. How she quit her job so she could travel the world, just like me. She overcame many difficulties in her life. And I liked listening to her stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we hadn’t seen each other since, we kept in contact for over a year. So I was excited to see her again. We had a week to work with, and weren’t quite sure what we were going to do. But I knew that we were going to visit her hometown and stay with her parents. And maybe go on a motorbike road trip. Whatever happened, I was excited to see my friend again. But I had to get there first…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;misadventures-in-travel&quot;&gt;Misadventures in Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flying from Christchurch to Hanoi, with an all-night layover in Singapore, was no short trip. And arriving at the airport, I was already ready for the long-haul. I separated my belongings into checked and carry-on luggage. Which, for me, meant taking my smaller bag out of my bigger bag, and filling it with my important items. I was ready. But after talking with the nice attendant at the check-in desk, I realized that I didn’t yet have my confirmation letter to gain entry into Vietnam. I was waiting on a response from Vietnamese immigration. But, they couldn’t let me fly until I had my letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before my year of travel, I would have panicked. But I was surprisingly calm. It was at this moment that I felt a bit of pride in my growth over the past year. But that quickly faded as I realized I needed to find a solution to my current dilemma. In addition to contacting the immigration department, I reapplied for the confirmation letter with a &quot;super-urgent&quot; request. That could still take up to four hours. I waited patiently in the food court. My flight was in one hour, and I didn’t receive any response. I went back to the staff and begged for them to let me fly. They gave me permission to fly only to Singapore. But I would have to have the confirmation letter ready to be checked-in to my next flight. I’ve never been so happy in my life. Backpacking New Zealand for the past month was tiring. I wanted my travels to go smoothly for just one time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Singapore was like a trip through time. I visited the city for a few days once. I spent three nights in this airport on layovers. And I used Singapore as a port to get to the volunteering I did in Indonesia. Anyways, I just mean to say that the Singapore airport was starting to feel like home. Spending my fourth night there was almost comfortable. Except for the fact that I still slept on the hard floor, and still awoke to armed police officers asking for passports and papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hanoi&quot;&gt;Hanoi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once in Hanoi, I took the public bus into the city, and checked into my hostel. While walking around Hanoi, I was reminded of the time I was last here to visit a friend, almost four years ago. People crowded around to eat on tiny plastic tables and chairs out in the street, motorbikes zooming by while honking incessantly, and smells of deliciously sweet food reminded me of my past adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to meet up with Van the next day. So I had plenty of time to take a nap. But she arrived in Hanoi that evening. And I wanted to see her. We had coffee with her good friend late at night. As I walked up to the coffee shop, I was so nervous. Was I really meeting Van after a year? It didn’t seem real to me. We had a casual conversation with her friend. And then walked around the city in the rain for a couple hours. We had ice cream and walked around a lake. It was really great to see her after such a long time. The next day we met up for lunch and met more AHAH volunteers for a frog hot pot at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;haiphong&quot;&gt;Haiphong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our Hanoi shenanigans, we took a bus to her hometown, on which we both slept. When we arrived, we met up with a friend of Van’s so we could borrow her motorbike. After driving to her parents’ house, we ate a special lunch that her father made: pork cooked with many spices and vegetables. Shortly after, using the motorbike, we explored the city. We ate many different foods at a market, but sadly I can’t remember the names. After deciding to travel by motorbike to Ninh Ninh, a beautiful area three hours South, we walked around the area close to her home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, Van took me to a local breakfast place to try Bánh Cuốn (rice noodle sheets, pork, vegetables, and sweet fish sauce). We went to a local coffee shop, where the coffee cup was kept in another cup of warm water. Previously, I had casually mentioned that I loved coffee and that I wanted to try special Bánh Cuốn. I admired Van’s thoughtfulness when she thought to find these places for me. And after having a talk about her previous experience with a motorbike road trip through Vietnam, we set off on our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ninh-binh&quot;&gt;Ninh Binh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we drove our bike out of the city, the noise and traffic slowly receded. We drove through more rural lands for about three hours. I much prefer the rural areas to the city any day. The city is stressful, chaotic, and polluted. Comparatively, the rural areas are relaxing, peaceful, and refreshing. The weather wasn’t too cold, but your hands went numb easily while driving. So Van and I shared the load. I had never driven this type of bike before. It wasn’t an automatic, but it wasn’t a manual either. It didn’t have a clutch, but it had a foot shifter. For the longest time, I didn’t realize I wasn’t shifting properly. Regardless, we eventually made it to our destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got there, we chose a seemingly random homestay in Trang An. It turned out phenomenal. It was right on the water, with bamboo walkways leading ever deeper. We walked around the ancient capital, which was quite relaxing compared to the motorbike trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days, as we explored the beautiful lakes and caves, Van and I became even closer. What was once a good friendship turned into something more. We went on a boat tour, tried to find stars during the cloudy nights, and just walked around the area. Although we only had a few days together in this magical place, it seemed like a lifetime. It was one of the beautiful moments in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode our bike back to Hanoi for an early dinner with a friend, and just relaxing for awhile. Because I had to fly home in the morning, I treasured every moment of the evening. And although it seemed to last forever, the morning did eventually come. And she drove me to the airport for my early flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right when I thought my travels and misadventures where coming to an end, we nearly ran out of gas. We drove around trying to find somewhere to fill up. And we eventually found a shop that sold gasoline by the liter out of bottles. This instantly took me back to my times motorbiking around in Indonesia. Nothing like a good scare at the end of your travels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we eventually made it to the airport. And the goodbye was easily the most difficult of goodbyes I’d ever experienced while traveling. But now I’m flying home. And she is staying in Vietnam. But we will meet up somewhere around the world later. I am quite sad, but also incredibly happy to have met her. She changed my life more than I thought anyone could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-home&quot;&gt;Going Home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to look forward to coming home. I haven’t seen my family or friends in a few months. And I’m starting my dream job soon. The present is delightful, future is bright, and I can’t wait to see what it holds. But I’ve learned to not have any expectations, and just go with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year of travel, I’ve become so much happier with myself. Because I have been able to improve my social skills, expand my perspective about the world, and organize my priorities in a manner more aligned with my beliefs. What an incredible year it has been. I can’t wait for the next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="vietnam" /><summary type="html">Eating mouthwatering food at every corner, watching stunning landscapes, walking across bamboo bridges, failing to speak Vietnamese, somehow floating on concrete boats, walking past do not enter signs, trying to catch a glimpse of monkeys, getting lost on a motorbike, and enjoying great company.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Life as a Kiwi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/12/10/life-as-a-kiwi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life as a Kiwi" /><published>2018-12-10T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/12/10/life-as-a-kiwi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/12/10/life-as-a-kiwi.html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I decided that I wanted to travel, New Zealand has been on the top of my list. I had heard many phenomenal stories about living the working holiday visa life down under as a kiwi. I heard stories of people buying camper vans, going on thousand mile bike tours, or working in ski resorts, as tour guides, or on farms. Before I heard about the earthquake and volunteer opportunity in Nepal, I was planning on doing a working holiday myself. It was my dream to buy a camper van and work on a farm in New Zealand for a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m unbelievably happy at how my travels have turned out, but I was also happy to spend some time here, even though it was only one month. And even though my &quot;camper van&quot; turned out to be a car that a grandma might drive…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;north-island&quot;&gt;North Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I’m not a huge Lord of the Rings fan, I watched the movies often as a kid. I had a few days to spend in the North Island, so I decided to take a LOTR tour. I visited Hobbiton, the location of The Shire, trekked Tongariro Alpine Crossing, which is the location of Mt. Doom, and visited other quick spots along the way down South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before crossing the Cook Straight, I camped at my first-come, first-served campsite, Grace’s Stream. I had the entire place to myself. So I enjoyed some hiking, and my first freeze-dried backpacker meals, some meditation, reading, and relaxing in a hammock. I even saw a kiwi dash across my path!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;south-island&quot;&gt;South Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crossing the ferry, I did my first multi-day hike in New Zealand, the Nydia Track. This trail took me along the edge of a few bays, with lush and fertile plants and strange creatures. I stayed at another first-come, first-served campsite about half way into the trek. Again, I had the entire place to myself. So, I relaxed by the shore of the bay, ate my dinner, listened to the rain, and read my book. It was a wonderfully relaxing and peaceful evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, after taking my time waking up and drying off my gear in the sun, I completed the trek with a return. I passed an old logging wharf, a pet tuna eel, and some bee honey farms. The views were stellar, the weather was perfect, and I has happy as can be. It was my first multi-day trek in New Zealand, and it was a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my trek, I continued my drive down South towards Christchurch to meet a friend. The drive took a couple of days, with gorgeous scenery at every turn. Again, I found a campsite where I was the only resident. Once I got to Christchurch, I spent a day there relaxing, and then I met my friend. She is a friend back home, who was able to take two weeks off work to join me in New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent our two weeks trekking a Great Walk, hiking up to a natural hot spring in the mountains, collecting jade on West Coast beaches, kayaking in lagoons, hiking up avalanche territory to spot Kea, and trekking through the wilderness on unmarked paths. It was an adventurous and exciting time, full of scenery from mountains to beaches to forests to lakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my friend left from Christchurch, I decided to head down South again. I spent a couple of days in Mount Cook National Park hiking around and visiting friends, but my favorite hike was to Mueller Hut. As you hiked up this steep snowy trail, you could hear avalanches from a nearby mountain. They sounded like thunder. The hike was challenging and rewarding at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I wanted to do another multi-day hike. This was the craziest hike of my life. Because I had been hiking so much over the past three weeks, I decided to pick an easy hike. But I didn’t really read the description of the trail. It was a near 50% incline for a few long kilometers. I got to Brewster Hut, which was beautifully placed on the edge of a cliff. And I met a guy who told me you could summit the entire mountain in just another couple of hours. So of course I did it. I ate lunch and dropped my bag off at the hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing upward, I scrambled over loose boulders and rocks, and newly fallen snow. With no trail markers, I had to try to navigate using only a few broken cairns here and there. The hike was the most intense, and dangerous hike I’ve ever been on. I felt like I was going to fall off the side of the mountain at any time. But the views were worth it. And the adrenaline rush was invigorating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked my way back down to the hut, slipping only a couple of times along the way. Memories of when I broke my rib while hiking the PCT came flooding back in storm. But I made it, and met others staying at the hut on the way. I read my book, and watched the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the trip, we stayed at backpacking huts, maintained by the Department of Conservation. These were such a treat to use when out in the wild. They come equipped with kitchens, bunk beds with mattresses, composting toilets, and water reservoirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Zealand did not disappoint. The trekking system here is extremely thought-out, expertly maintained, and wonderful to use. I can’t wait to come back to this magical land.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Climbing mountains, tramping trails, camping along rivers, floating in natural hot springs, kayaking in lagoons, listening to robotic birds, eating fish and chips, being eaten by sand fleas, discovering the magical tree-fern, swinging on bridges, sliding down snow drifts, and trying to not cause avalanches.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hiking the Great Wild Wall of China</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/china/2018/11/10/hiking-the-great-wild-wall-of-china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiking the Great Wild Wall of China" /><published>2018-11-10T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/china/2018/11/10/hiking-the-great-wild-wall%E2%80%93of-china</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/china/2018/11/10/hiking-the-great-wild-wall-of-china.html">&lt;p&gt;Backpacking through China was an unforgettable experience. Compared to traveling in the United States, Europe, or even Hong Kong, China is an entirely separate world. The cultural differences are stark, but I still learned quite a few lessons. Yes, they have a communist government, the food is entirely different, most major companies are blocked on the internet, and education/work are strictly valued. But when talking with individual people, I noticed that we aren’t really so different. Just like any other place I’ve visited, I find people to be kind, welcoming, and enthusiastic about life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in addition to the wonderful people, the natural side of China is breathtaking. From East to West, China has so much to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting my trip off in Beijing, I immediately made moves to see the Great Wall. Just like any touristy area in another country, hostels had tours available. But these don’t necessarily show the true, local side of a country. They would put you in a chartered van with other foreigners, give you lunch, take you to a place where everyone else goes, and basically do everything for you. And this isn’t bad for everyone; I’m sure some people would rather enjoy the experience. But it’s not for me. I wanted to plan everything on my own. By doing so, I believe I have more of an adventure, meet locals, and try to survive on my own in a totally new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiking-the-great-wild-wall–of-china/IMG_1434.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I began by finding out exactly where I wanted to go. The Great Wall is, well, great. With thousands of kilometers of wall to choose from, where do you go? Well, I knew a friend who just recently backpacked China. And she recommended that I visit Jiankou, a rugged and wild part of the Great Wall. So, I Googled the transportation to the nearby city of Xizhazi. I could take a couple of buses, or a taxi. I decided on the buses because they’re always more prone to adventure. After navigating my way around by signs all in Chinese, and catching the first bus to a city north of Beijing, I caught a local bus to Xizhazi. I was the only foreigner on the bus. The section of wall I was hiking was not popular with foreign tourists. So, the only people on the bus were locals of the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://maps.google.com/maps?width=100%25&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=箭扣长城&amp;amp;output=embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I arrived, I set up my gear and set off to hike the wall. After reaching the top of the wall, I hiked along for a bit. The top of the wall was broken and crumbling, with trees growing out of the top, but there was a clear footpath. After a short while, I came to a section of wall that was so steep and hazardous, that I couldn’t believe that people climbed the part. I decided to take a rest and think about whether or not I wanted to continue. As I was snacking, a group of local tourists from Shanghai approached. Yao, one of the people in their group who spoke a little English, started talking to me about the hike. He offered me to show me the ropes, or lack thereof. I ended up joining their hiking party and it was the best decision of my trip in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiking-the-great-wild-wall–of-china/IMG_1685.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it was a little difficult at first with the language barrier, we had a great time hiking the ruins of the Great Wall together. Yao, who knew quite a bit about the wall, informed us as a tour guide would have. I also met Andrew and Lucy, who owned their own headwear manufacturing business. They had clients in the United States and Canada, some of which I’ve actually bought clothes from. I met another couple, May and 汪舰. May owned a yoga studio, and 汪舰 was a software engineer like myself. And all of the others were equally as interesting, but they didn’t speak much English, so it was difficult for me to get to know them. Regardless, we all bonded along the hike. They treated me as if I was a long-term friend of their group. They invited me to hike 30 kilometers with them tomorrow, and to a dinner that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiking-the-great-wild-wall–of-china/IMG_1674.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we arrived at their guest house in Xizhazi, they talked with the owner to get me my own room. I was so thankful, because I was actually planning on camping along the wall, and it was below freezing that night. As the table for dinner was being setup, I started to realize what was in store. An enormous table, with an equally as large lazy-suzan, was brought out. The table fit eleven people, and the lazy-suzan fit all of the food. In China, it is customary for everyone to share the food. From the rotating lazy-suzan. All of the dining utensils, including plates, bowls, chopsticks, and teacups were individually wrapped in plastic. Apparently, many Chinese restaurants outsource dishwashing, and the outsourced company returns the dishes wrapped. When the food actually came, I was stunned by the intoxicating aromas of so many dishes. I can’t remember any of the names, but all of the flavors were so vivid. Except when I accidentally took a bite of fermented tofu. As a toast to new friends, we drank Chinese rice wine. Once finished, we rested up for our big hike tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiking-the-great-wild-wall–of-china/IMG_1558.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we had a quick breakfast before starting our journey. We would hike from Xizhazi to Mutianyu, the touristy and restored section of the wall. It was a fantastic day full of adventure. I bonded with my new-found friends by soaking in the views, sharing our lunches with each other, and taking so many pictures of everyone. I don’t think I’ve ever really posed for a picture until this trip. They really showed me how it’s done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hiking-the-great-wild-wall–of-china/group.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the touristy parts, the difference was shocking. The wall had been completely restored, and there were hoards of people. I didn’t like it at all. So hurried through as fast as we could. And after hiking back to the start, my friends helped me get back to Beijing. We said our goodbyes and they were quite sad, even though they were only temporary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of my China trip, I spontaneously decided to visit Shanghai to stay with Andrew, Lucy, and their two boys. We met up with the entire group for another enormous dinner, tried yoga at May’s yoga studio, made baozi (dumplings), and explored Shanghai. I’m so thankful to have met all of these extraordinary people by chance on my Great Wall trip. I will never forget them and I hope they visit me one day at my home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="china" /><summary type="html">Straying off the beaten path, making life-long friends, and exploring the ruins of an ancient wall.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Backpacking through Southern China and Hiking Tiger Leaping Gorge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/11/07/backpacking-through-southern-china-and-hiking-tiger-leaping-gorge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Backpacking through Southern China and Hiking Tiger Leaping Gorge" /><published>2018-11-07T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/11/07/backpacking-through-southern-china-and-hiking-tiger-leaping-gorge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/11/07/backpacking-through-southern-china-and-hiking-tiger-leaping-gorge.html">&lt;p&gt;After having spent a couple weeks exploring China, I’d climbed the wild and rugged Great Wall, taught English in Xi’an, climbed the famous Huashan mountain, eaten spicy hot pot in Chengdu, and visited an old thatched cottage of a famous poet. But I was still looking for another thrilling adventure. After traveling by train for a couple days, I made my way to one of the most beautiful villages in China, Lijang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://maps.google.com/maps?width=100%25&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=Lijiang,%20Yunnan,%20China&amp;amp;output=embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lijang is situated in-between mountains on all sides, towering above the manmade city. I stayed in a small guest house, with a couple of other travelers. And because I was actually a little sick during that time, I extended my stay to rest a couple days. And I’m so thankful I did, because I wouldn’t have met the people I did. I met a South Korean girl, Suin, who had been a well-experienced traveler, traveling for a few years to countless countries. I met an American girl, Kim, who had just finished teaching English in China for the past year. And I met a French guy, Vincent, who was once a web developer who quit his job to travel the world. While spending a couple days at the guest house, I found out that all three of the people I met wanted to hike Tiger Leaping Gorge. So we decided to take a chartered van together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an early start to the morning, we hopped on our bus for a smooth and straightforward ride to the trail start. Compared to my Great Wall public bus adventure, this was a piece of cake. I have to admit, it was nice taking private transport this time. After buying our tickets into the national park, our van dropped us off at the trail head. With all of our bags packed and situated, we strode off up the twisting streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 30 minutes of the hike was essentially just walking through a village. Once we got to the actual trail, we were faced with a near vertical, rocky path. A local man, tethered to a couple donkeys, sat close by. He approached us with keen eyes, gesturing to his donkeys. Fortunately, Suin spoke Mandarin fluently and told the man that we wouldn’t be needing any help from the animals. But he followed us anyway, obviously having done this before. So, with our new companion, we trekked on and up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fairly strenuous hike, and Kim and Suin eventually did accept the man’s offer to use the donkeys. Vincent and I trekked ahead, eventually meeting another couple of people. Coincidentally, we ran into another American girl and another South Korean girl, who had also just met on the trail. The American girl, Janelle, had been studying abroad in Shanghai. And the South Korean girl, Choi, was on holiday for a short time. After talking for some time, we realized that we were staying at the same guest house along the trail. So we continued to hike together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views were absolutely stunning. As we hiked up the brutal switchbacks, the snowy mountain range appeared larger and larger. We passed a few local shops or guest houses along the way. One man was actually selling marijuana along the side of the trail. Apparently, the plant grows wild in the mountains here. After taking many much-needed breaks along the way, we eventually made it to our guest house, The Tea Horse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view from the guest house was phenomenal. Kim and Suin made it not long after us. We checked in, and had a couple beers on top of the roof. Although the beer in China is light, it was such a rewarding refreshment at the top. And it was even better sharing with friends. Afterwards, we ate dinner together. I truly enjoyed being with this group of people. Everyone was kind, and had unique stories to tell. And although I dropped food with chopsticks on more than one occasion, I devoured the yak meat quickly. By the end of dinner, we were all so tired that we went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up at 04:30 was the best decision I made on this trip. Without any lights to pollute the night sky, the stars shown with a brilliant light. The others had also made plans to get up this early, but no one was in sight. So, I stayed on top of the roof, listening to music, and staring at the endlessly marvelous expanse of our universe. This was one of the happiest moments of my travels in China. I was at peace with myself and what I was doing. The only thing that mattered was the current moment. I had met good people, ate delicious food, and seen wonderful sights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that morning, we had breakfast and quickly headed on our way. Throughout the hike, we met goats, picked wild fruit, stared at stunning views, posed for many photos, chased waterfalls, and climbed steep ladders. At the end of the hike, we climbed down into the gorge itself and were rewarded with close up views of the water rushing through rocks lines with strata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We climbed back up, had dinner, and took the bus back to Lijang. Janelle and I decided to travel together in Lijang for the next couple of days. We went to Jade Dragon Snow Mountain, which was 4506 meters above sea level. We saw more of China’s stunning beauty by touching blue water, finding wild horses, and relaxing in a meadow on top of a mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading down South in China was quite the experience that I won’t soon forget. I met many wonderful people, and had thrilling adventures with them all. And honestly, it was one of the happiest times of my life. I’m still uncertain as to why this was, but I felt like I was finally becoming the person I’ve always wanted to be. Socializing with people was easy. I was able to have great conversations, which led to greater friendships, which led to the greatest experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Another phenomenal adventure full of hiking stunning landscapes, petting wild goats, crossing rickety bridges, chasing waterfalls, climbing steep ladders, picking wild fruit, dropping food with chopsticks, and enjoying the company of so many new friends.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Icelandic Voyage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/10/03/an-icelandic-voyage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Icelandic Voyage" /><published>2018-10-03T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/10/03/an-icelandic-voyage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/10/03/an-icelandic-voyage.html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://maps.google.com/maps?width=100%25&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=Iceland&amp;amp;output=embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two months of studying for job interviews, I was just about ready for another adventure. I had my final Google interview on Friday, and we left on the following Monday. It was crazy and chaotic, but well worth the effort. But it was time to travel again. I didn’t realize how much I had missed the thrill of the adventure. Iceland showed me what a trip with great people was like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0694.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of my best friends, Neil and Matt, and I decided to jump on a plane and head to an island that is being torn in half, literally. Iceland lays on a divergent tectonic plate interaction. Meaning two plates are moving apart. This results in a landscape of stunning geological diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1101.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rented a 4x4 for the week. And just took off. We brought all of our camping gear and 16 servings of freeze-dried meals each. Our plan was to just drive around the island, and stop off at places that looked cool… And it worked. I mean, we definitely did our research before hand by creating a map. But it still felt like we were just following the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0719.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0701.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After gathering some supplies in Reykjavik, we drove West along a peninsula towards the Snæfellsjökull National Park. We saw many sheep, rainbows, scattered rocks, black sandy beaches, craters, and canyons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent our first night camping somewhere in the park. We cooked our freeze-dried backpacker meals, drank some whiskey, and had some good conversation. But it didn’t last long before the night chill came in. That night I experienced the first of many Icelandic winds. My tent was clearly not suited for such high-speed winds. But it survived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1132.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1121.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1120.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1116.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we continued around the peninsula clockwise, visiting equally as stunning waterfalls, as well as some touristy places. And that night, we camped along the top of a mountain. But we made sure to find a place that would hide us from the wind. That night, we stayed up late. We were rewarded with a glimpse at the Aurora. We only saw one “ribbon” but it was still beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1127.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0924.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0929.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0904.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we continued back East. Seeing more waterfalls and beautiful landscapes. We decided to head into the center of the island towards Thórsmörk. We found an incredible campsite that was in a crater, on top of a mountain, with a river flowing through it. The place was fertile and so much fun to explore. Some brave souls had brought a picnic table down into the crater. So we set up base for the night, but not before exploring the caves, canyon, and river. Neil and Matt found a bridge to help us cross the river to a more desirable camping spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night actually proved to be one of the worst storms I had ever been camping in. The wind ripped my tent out of the ground, and it was raining hard. Everything got soaked. But it was fun and we were laughing about it in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-4&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0928.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we had to dry our gear off in a cave, which didn’t really work. Anyway we packed our stuff up and ran to the car in the rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0943.GIF&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing about the infamously treacherous winds in Iceland, we had to see, and feel, them for ourselves. So, we went to the top of a cliff on the edge of the island. And we were not disappointed. The wind was so strong that we could barely open the car door. While crawling to the edge of the cliff, Neil lost his hat in the wind. We could actually stand sideways against the wind and not fall down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1084.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0945.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0947.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0953.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to another waterfall, Skógafoss, had $20 fish and chips, and went to Reynisfjara Beach (a black sand beach with dolomite columns).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_0984.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1027.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finding another beautiful campsite along a river and canyon, we explored around. The water was crystal clear and perfect for drinking. And there was not too much wind and no rain. Compared to last night, this was heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-5&quot;&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1065.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we packed up and header towards a glacial lagoon. Before making our way back to Reykjavik, we stopped by this iceberg-full lake for some quick and easy views. It was touristy compared to our other experiences. People crowded the shores, but the views were still nice. But I still much prefer to be out in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1038.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1052.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before getting back to Reykjavik, we stopped by another black sand beach for some quick walking, met some horses, and saw a beautiful sunset. Once in Reykjavik, we found our hostel. We paid the most I’ve ever paid for accommodation while traveling, about $60 a person for a dorm bed. But the hostel was nice. And it was great to take a shower and unpack a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1072.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ate some of our backpacker meals in the kitchen of the hostel, because food in Iceland is insanely expensive. Matt was kind enough to offer Neil and I a couple of his meals. Neil and Matt wanted a night out on the town in Reykjavik, so we set off for a night of shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-6&quot;&gt;Day 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1073.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all of the driving around and camping not too far from the car, Neil wanted to go on a longer trip. So we headed back up to Thórsmörk to do a two day hike. We actually passed our previous campsite, and continued through tons of fords. I was thankful to Neil because he was the only one who knew how to drive a manual car. We stopped at every river crossing to scope it out, and we were careful crossing. But eventually we found a ford that did not look passable in our little Dacia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1082.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking around for a half an hour or so, we went back to the car, only to now notice that we had a flat tire. We weren’t that scared even though we were in the middle of nowhere without any cell service. We had a few days worth of food and unlimited water. But Neil and Matt had changed many tires before. So they got to work on swapping the flat with our spare. And even though we had a setback, the views were some of the best I’d seen in Iceland. Such a beautiful country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that was fixed, we drove as carefully as we had ever driven before to get back to the main road. We decided to skip the long hike this time for safety. Sometimes that is the best decision, however disappointing. But we still had a backup plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1089.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1087.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to a geothermal park full of colorful geysers, and actual trees. There aren’t many in Iceland. We found a camping spot in the woods, and I slept in the car. My camping gear was finally dry, an rain was in the forecast. I didn’t want to travel with wet gear. Best decision of my life. We sat around with our headlamps, drank a couple of our Icelandic beers, and told stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-7&quot;&gt;Day 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/an-icelandic-voyage/IMG_1096.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to end our trip by visiting a famous tomato farm. We all got an unlimited tomato soup and bread buffet. Such a delicious way to end our trip. After, Neil and Matt drove me to the airport so I could fly onward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all of the rapidly changing and intense weather, I had a great time in Iceland. Being with good friends who are enthusiastic about backpacking was a huge plus. I’m so thankful I have friends who will come with me on trips like this. I’m sure that my trip would not have been the same without them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Navigating the Icelandic roads between fissures, craters, volcanoes, glaciers, and mountains.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hiking the Ozark Trail in Missouri</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hiking/usa/missouri/2018/07/16/hiking-the-ozark-trail-in-missouri.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiking the Ozark Trail in Missouri" /><published>2018-07-16T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hiking/usa/missouri/2018/07/16/hiking-the-ozark-trail-in-missouri</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hiking/usa/missouri/2018/07/16/hiking-the-ozark-trail-in-missouri.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been hiking in many diverse places around the world such as the Himalayas in Nepal, the volcanoes of Indonesia, pilgrimage routes in Japan, city-overlooking mountains in Hong Kong, or the Cascades in Washington. But it was nice to come back home to explore my own backyard, full of fertile and flowing rivers, springs with waters so clean you could drink directly from them (even though we used Iodine), and shut-ins, large slabs of marbled rock with water flowing over them. But it wasn’t all good. We trekked though jungles of Stinging Nettle, sweated through the blistering heat, and got caught in one of the biggest thunderstorms of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neil, Megan, Matt and I started off by camping directly on the river, our tents just a few meters away from the brisk water. In order to reach our camp, we had to walk through a mostly flooded road. But the location was worth it. We had a full view of the stars at night. The Milky Way cluster was right above our heads, shining in all of its brilliance. Mars, positioned right above the river, was the brightest it had been in fifteen years. We saw three gigantic meteors, and a lightning storm off in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning, we took a quick swim in the Current River, leaning into the fast-flowing waters, and then packed up camp and made our way along the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the quick swim in the brisk water cooled us off a bit, the 95˚F heat of the day promptly took hold. But it wasn’t all bad; Being in the forest most of the time helped mitigate the heat. One section of the trail had large quantities of Stinging Nettle, plants with tiny barbs that would cause your skin to sting and itch for a short time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After bushwhacking our way through the jungles of hell, we found an opening to the river where we immediately swam and had lunch. Our spot was just down-river from a spring, so the cool water eased our minds and irritated skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about an hour or so, we headed out on the trail again. We hiked under the shade of the forest canopy, and crossed the Indian River three times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hike was too long and hot to bring all of our water with us, so we brought filters and Iodine tablets with us to purify our drinking water. But to be honest, I think we could have quenched our thirst directly from any of the rivers or springs we passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night, we camped at Rocky Creek Shut-Ins, swam in the clear, flowing waters, and explored an old abandoned mill. After relaxing and cooling off, it was almost time for bed after a long day. We didn’t think it was going to rain, but it ended up pouring and thundering most of the night. Our tents held up, but water flowed underneath. Matt, who was in the worst spot, moved up the hill. Megan, who was only in a hammock, had to move in with me, where we cowered from the thunder and incessant wind most of the night. Neil, who had recently bought a new tent, and happened to be on a small hill and was completely dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we hung our tents up to dry inside the old mill. Megan, Neil and I hiked back to the start of the trail while Matt stayed to watch and dry out our belongings. The hike back was much cooler than the previous day. And without our packs we finished in no time. We drove back to Matt, who had organized all of our freshly dry gear. Thanks, Matt! We packed up, swam in the water once more, found three Water Moccasins (maybe), and headed home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the trials and tribulations we endured throughout this hike, it was still a great outing with friends, away from the city and surrounded by all sorts of beautiful nature.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="hiking" /><category term="usa" /><category term="missouri" /><summary type="html">Exploring the many rivers, springs, shut-ins, and abandoned buildings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning to Scuba Dive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/usa/florida/2018/06/24/learning-to-scuba-dive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning to Scuba Dive" /><published>2018-06-24T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-06-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/usa/florida/2018/06/24/learning-to-scuba-dive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/usa/florida/2018/06/24/learning-to-scuba-dive.html">&lt;p&gt;In mid-June, I undertook the challenge and adventure of becoming open-water certified in scuba diving with my family. We learned about all of the equipment, techniques, and physical skills necessary for breathing under, and swimming on top of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started out with two confined-water dives in a hotel swimming pool. First, we completed a few swimming tests including treading water for ten minutes and swimming 500 yards. We also learned all the essential skills such as setting up and putting on our gear, breathing techniques, and even emergency situation scenarios. We had to show that we could deal with running out of air while underwater. Our fabulous instructors turned off our air supplies, and our buddy swam over to give us their secondary regulator. The confined dives were informational, but we were ready to head out into the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diving in a swimming pool did not prepare me for what was to come out in the ocean. The colorful corals were teeming with a diversity of life. Curious sharks, giant barracudas lingering in the shadows under the boat, crabs scuttling across the ocean floor, lobsters taking refuge in a small cave, and schools of iridescent fish hiding under corals. Swimming in the deep water was like flying. But it wasn’t all fun and games; We had work to do too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished up our training over two days in the ocean. We practiced what we learned in the confined water dive. And we also learned other skills that were not possible in a swimming pool, such as navigating with a compass, or emergency ascents. Now that I am open-water certified, so much more of the world has opened up to me. I can’t wait to see what’s next!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="usa" /><category term="florida" /><summary type="html">Diving with sharks, swimming through caves, and learning new skills under the water.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What Being On My Own Has Taught Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/06/05/what-being-on-my-own-has-taught-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Being On My Own Has Taught Me" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/06/05/what-being-on-my-own-has%20taught-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/06/05/what-being-on-my-own-has-taught-me.html">&lt;p&gt;After eight months of being on my own out in this world, I’m bound to learn something about myself, other people, or the world in general. And I believe I have. I improved my social skills, I reordered my priorities, and I wrote more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;branching-out-and-growing-accustomed-to-living-outside-of-my-comfort-zone&quot;&gt;Branching out, and growing accustomed to living outside of my comfort zone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before embarking on my journey, I would have considered myself rather introverted. I was shy around strangers, especially when there was no purpose for conversation. I typically avoided people, even if I needed help with directions or information. On occasion, I would have actually rather walked five miles, then confront someone and ask about how the public transportation functioned. And that’s not just because I like walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my top priorities while walking around these past eight months was to learn to become more extroverted. I started slowly at first, but then, as it became easier, I flourished. I started off by putting myself in situations where I would talk with people. I would jump at any opportunity to meet someone new. Whether it was going up to a random group of people at a hostel and striking up a conversation, meeting someone on Couchsurfing to explore the city, or proactively arranging dinners, coffee dates, or activities with people that I knew I would be in contact with in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, as I had more and more practice with conversing with people, and the anxiety started to fade, I focused on having good conversations. I needed to first define what a good conversation meant to me. For me, a good conversation involves learning as much about the other person(s) with whom I am talking. Keeping the focus and topic of conversation on the other person(s), rather than myself. I tried to actively listen, and to ask relevant questions that would further the conversation. Only when the other person actually asked a question about myself would I talk about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to be more optimistic. Smile more. Only talk about positive thoughts. Or if it is unavoidable, talk about a negative thought in a positive way. Look at the bright side. At first, this was slightly forced. But over time, as I actively learned more about the people I was around, I started to gather a growing empathy for everyone. I felt genuinely happy for other people when they achieved something, or told a story about their own life. By having good conversations with people, I cared for them more. This really showed during my time in Nepal, where I spent four months around the same group of people. Living together, working together, and playing together made it easy to learn more and more about others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;worrying-less-about-material-possessions&quot;&gt;Worrying less about material possessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before heading out, I knew that I wanted to worry less about my stuff. But I never thought it would be possible. In previous travels, I met people who would just leave their belongings on their dorm bed, where anyone could just take it. I also met people who would entrust their entire bag to a stranger. And these weren’t strictly personal belongings that had no intrinsic value. Laptops, cameras, passports, or phones were among these belongings. I was completely taken aback in these situations. How could someone just leave all of their belongings somewhere like that? I would be worrying constantly. So much so that I wouldn’t enjoy the current moment. I eventually found a solution, but it was far from what I ever expected to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of just learning to worry less, I had an entire shift in my priorities and thinking. By having better conversations with people, making genuine friends, and enjoying people’s company more, I started to value my experiences more than my possessions. And those are impossible to steal. Obviously, I still carried my phone, passport, and wallet on me in sketchy situations, but I was completely fine with leaving my laptop, camera, and entire backpack somewhere vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to worrying less, I actually used my possessions less. Most of the time, especially in Nepal, I didn’t have internet access. I never used my phone or laptop. And because of this I was able to enjoy the company of others. The current moment, the people around me, and truly living became more important than my things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;worrying-less-about-the-future-and-planning&quot;&gt;Worrying less about the future and planning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t say that I am a planner necessarily, but I do like to have a little certainty about the future. During the last eight months, nothing was certain. I had no idea what was next. And at first, I worried about it. But as time went on, and I learned how to enjoy the current moment by making good friends and having great experiences. And the future became less important. I wasn’t able to cut out worrying entirely. But I am more comfortable accepting the fact that what will happen, will happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-in-all&quot;&gt;All In All&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By learning to have meaningful conversations, worrying less, and living in the current moment, I had a happier life. I was able to branch out and leave my comfort zone. And I was able to truly understand what was important to me as a person. I’m incredibly lucky to have had an experience such as this. And I hope to continue having them in the future!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Pondering how my experiences volunteering, traveling, and adventuring around the world changed me as a person.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/what-being-on-my-own-has%20taught-me/cover.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/what-being-on-my-own-has%20taught-me/cover.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Interpreting Signs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/06/03/interpreting-signs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interpreting Signs" /><published>2018-06-03T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/06/03/interpreting-signs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/06/03/interpreting-signs.html">&lt;p&gt;Getting lost is much easier when you don’t have any help from people or the signs they post. And I did just that in almost every country I visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;japan&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiking in Japan was challenging because all of the signs and trail-markers were written in Japanese. Because most Japanese people don’t speak English, this is the case for most of Japan, even in the cities. Fortunately, some of the more important signs had pictures on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if a sign happened to have some English written on it, it was usually broken, grammatically incorrect, or just difficult to interperet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned Hiragana and Katakana, two phonetic components of the Japanese writing system. With knowing these syllabaries, I could sound out certain words in Japanese. And when a word that is written in Katakana is spoken, it sometimes sounds like an English word. For example, in the image above, &quot;たばこ&quot; means tobacco because &quot;た&quot; sounds like ‘ta’ &quot;ば&quot; sounds like ‘ba’ and &quot;こ&quot; sounds like ‘ko.’ This was extremely helpful. But for the most part, I was still helplessly lost when trying to interpret a sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thailand&quot;&gt;Thailand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the touristy areas of Thailand, English is everywhere. You only really run into issues when you venture out into the rural areas. When driving up to the border of Laos in Thailand in a rental car, I could not rely on any signs to help me navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;indonesia&quot;&gt;Indonesia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English is also spoken well in more touristy areas in Indonesia. And there are even signs in English on more popular hikes. But hiking off the beaten trail provides a much more authentic experience because there is no English. Even though I learned a number of words in Bahasa (Indonesia’s national language) each province has it’s own local language!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hong-kong&quot;&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Hong Kong, most people speak English, as well as a variety of other languages. Hong Kong is an impressively culturally diverse place. But many signs are still in Chinese. They aren’t necessary to get around, but they are still entertaining to decipher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-whats-the-big-deal&quot;&gt;So What’s The Big Deal?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being able to read signs or talk to people isn’t so bad if you have internet or a map. But while traveling, I try to avoid the internet. And although having a map is nice, they aren’t always available.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Finding my way around when I can't read signs or talk to anyone.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>